《外星居民》前情提要
Previously on "Resident Alien"
诊所的杰伊
Jay at the clinic.
是阿斯塔的女儿
That's Asta's daughter.
这是个大秘密  并且如果被揭露
That's a really big secret, and it's gonna hurt
会伤害很多人
a lot of people when it comes out.
放手
Let go!
我以为没有我她会过得更好
I thought she'd be better off without me,
但如果不是那样呢
but what if that's not true?
住手  他不值得
Stop! He's not worth it.
如果她应该和我在一起呢
What if she's supposed to be with me?
-我听说他们发现了一具尸体  -不  只有一只脚
- I hear they found a body.  - No, just a foot.
有具尸体还没找到
There's a dead body out there somewhere,
我们找不到就誓不罢休
and we're not gonna rest until we find it.
我儿子麦克斯告诉我你是外星人
My son Max told me you're an alien.
坦白说  他快把我逼疯了
Frankly, he is driving me crazy.
我相信你  我有个计划
I believe you. I've got a plan.
有人吗
Hello?
-看看这个   -不
- Check this out.  - No!
你是怎么进来的
How did you get in here?
我有钥匙
I have a key.
我仍然是你的妻子
I am still your wife.
五年前
纽约市
哈里用组织样本来追踪感染
Harry used the tissue samples to track back the infection
发现其来自患者人工主动脉瓣的涂层
to the coating on the patient's artificial aortic valve.
-干得太棒了  哈利  -谢谢
- It was amazing work, Harry.  - Thank you.
只要不是我自己的心脏就好
I'm great with the heart as long as it's not my own.
失陪
Excuse me.
当然
Yes, of course.
你能帮帮我吗  不好意思
Hi, can you help me? I'm sorry.
你觉得这幅画在表达什么
What do you think this painting is saying?
我其实正在努力不去想它
I'm rather trying not to think about it, actually.
但是我觉得...
But I'd say...
它让我觉得有点上下颠倒
makes me feel a bit upside down.
上下颠倒
Upside down.
你有什么感觉
What's it make you feel?
我不知道
I don't know.
但我喜欢谜团
But I love the mystery.
好吧
Right.
很有趣
That's very interesting.
你真的应该和作者分享这种解读
You really ought to share that interpretation with the artist.
那就是我
Oh, that's me.
我是伊莎贝尔
Hi, I'm Isabelle.
-你是作者  -我是作者
- You're the artist?  - I'm the artist.
但我还以为你是女服务员
But I thought you were the waitress.
我在潜伏
I'm undercover.
我是女服务员  那你是谁
I'll be the waitress.Who will you be?
我是离婚的医生...
I am the divorced doctor...
也在潜伏
who is also undercover.
我是个艺术爱好者
I'm an art afficionado.
作为一个艺术爱好者  你对此有何看法
As an art afficionado, what do you say about this?
我喜欢这幅画
I love this painting.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我是哈里·万德斯本格
I'm Harry Vanderspeigle.
你是哈里·万德...什么
You're Harry Vander... What's it?
-斯本格 -斯本格
- Speigle, yes. Yes.  -Speigle.
可惜有个混蛋出价比你高
Unfortunately, some bastard has outbid you.
一个混蛋出价比我高
A bastard outbid me?
-的确如此  -混蛋
- Indeed.  -Bastard.
我得搞定它
Got to fix that.
等等
Hold on.
一万
$10,000.
我是说  这是有原因的
I mean, it's for a good cause.
是的
Right.
的确
Indeed.
那我可不能错过
I'm not letting this get away.
我想解开这个谜团
I want to solve this mystery.
*有个男孩*
*There was a boy*
*一个奇特而迷人的男孩*
*A very strange, enchanted boy*
*人们说他走得很远*
*They say he wandered very far*
*非常远*
*Very far*
*越过陆地和海洋*
*Over land and sea*
外星居民
第一季第五集
人类有一种奇怪的行为
Humans have a strange practice
他们称之为"扯淡的艺术"
they call "The art of bullshitting,"
现在
那个小杂种麦克斯就是扯淡界的米开朗基罗
and that little bastard Max is Michelangelo.
我讨厌那个孩子
I hate that kid.
你想假装是我的朋友
You want to pretend to be my friend
然后偷了我的钥匙闯进我的小屋
to steal my keys and break into my cabin?
没问题
Fine with me.
很高兴认识你  朋友
Nice knowing you, friend.
什么
What?
有人吗  有人吗
Hello? Hello?
-有人吗  有...  -麦克斯
- Hello? H...  - Max!
谢天谢地  你在这里
Oh, thank God, you were in here.
你刚才没检查壁橱吗
You didn't check the closet?
看看里面有没有我们熟睡的儿子吗
For our sleeping son?
没有  我没有检查壁橱或袜子抽屉
No, I didn't check the closet or the sock drawers.
他有时会在这里露营
He camps out in here sometimes.
你一定是睡着了
Oh, you must have fallen asleep.
-过来  -是的
- Come here.  - Yeah.
我一定是睡着了
I must have fallen asleep.
不
No!
好了  我需要知道
All right, now, I'm gonna need to know
男孩的血型
the boy's blood type,
还需要一个头发样本
and I'm gonna need a hair sample.
我们要乐观  但要做好最坏的准备
We gonna hope for the best but be prepared for the worst.
副警长  你上去他的房间收集指纹
Now, Deputy, you go up, and you dust his room for prints.
告诉我  上次见到那个男孩还活着
Now, tell me, when was the last time
是什么时候
you saw the boy alive?
麦克斯闹乌龙了
Well, so, funny story about Max.
他刚才在壁橱里
He was in the closet.
你在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
妈的  我还为了这事刮了车上的冰
Shit, I scraped ice off the truck for this?
事实上  是我刮的
Actually, I scraped the ice.
很抱歉把你拖到这里来
Yeah, we're really sorry to drag you out here.
然后趁他喝咖啡的时候给车里开暖了空调
Then I warmed up the car while he finished his coffee.
你不如给你儿子系条绳子
Look, you might want to tie a rope
这样他就不会丢了
around your boy so you don't lose him.
你知道吗  我今天看到他骑自行车
You know I caught him riding his bike
沿着16号公路出城
way out on Route 16 today?
什么  麦克斯  是真的吗
What? Max, is that true?
你知道我们不允许你
You know you're not allowed
骑自行车离家那么远的
to ride your bike that far from home.
你被禁足一年
You are grounded for a year.
-亲爱的  -一天
- Honey.  - A day?
你不能让我禁足  我有充分的理由
You can't ground me! I had a good reason!
是得有点理由
This should be something.
如果我儿子说他有充分的理由
Hey, if my son says he has a good reason,
那他肯定没说谎  说吧  麦克斯
he had a good reason. Go ahead, Max.
谢谢你  妈妈
Thank you, Mother.
我得趁万德斯本格医生工作的时候
I had to break in to Dr. Vanderspeigle's house
-闯进他的家  -等等  什么
- while he was at work.  - Wait, what?
接受道歉
Apology accepted.
你们家教的
What type of criminal mastermind
这是什么犯罪主谋啊
you are raising in this house, huh?
我找到了证据能证明他是外星人
I found proof that he's an alien!
是吗  什么样的证据
Oh, really? What kind of proof?
比如...飞行的球体  或是...
Like, uh, flying orbs or a loss of, uh...
消失的时间
uh, time.
他的地下室有外星人的科技
He has alien technology in his basement!
麦克斯  你不能再说谎了
Max, you have to stop lying.
我没说谎  萨哈尔也在
I'm not lying! Sahar was there!
她都看到了
She saw everything!
我不记得看到了什么
I don't remember seeing anything.
什么
What?
我记得在骑车  但...
I remember riding bikes, but...
我不记得去过医生的小屋
I don't remember going to the doctor's cabin.
对不起  麦克斯
I'm sorry, Max.
你还没走
You're still here.
你不能穿那个
You can't wear that.
那是男人的衣服
That is a man's shirt!
我飞了大半个国家来找你谈谈
I flew across the country to talk to you,
而你却转身开车走了
and you left and drove away.
你去哪了
Where did you go?
买牛奶
To get milk.
那牛奶呢
So where's the milk?
我喝了
I drank it.
她在扫描我
She's scanning me.
幸好我没杀了那两个孩子
It's a good thing I didn't murder those kids.
不然一裤子都得是血
There'd be blood all over my pants.
那我就只能把她也杀了
And then I'd have to murder her.
对  我做了正确的决定
Yes. I made the right choice.
这是我的强项
I'm very good at this.
你有什么不一样了
What's different about you?
我刮了胡子
I shaved my mustache.
你以前也不留胡子
You didn't have a mustache.
长出来了  然后我给刮了
I grew it, and then I shaved it...
刮完才喝的牛奶
before I drank the milk.
你嗑药了吗
Are you high?
对
Yes.
我抽了超强效的大麻
I am high on the skunk's...weed.
我非常生你的气
I'm very cross with you.
你那语气就像詹姆斯·邦德
You sound like James Bond.
非常生你的气
Very cross with you.
我非常生你的气
I'm very cross with you.
我都准备好签离婚协议了
I was ready to sign the divorce papers,
而你却拖了律师们好几个月
and then you stonewalled the lawyers for months.
电话  邮件  短信  通通不回
Phone calls, emails, texts, all unanswered.
我不知道你有没有收到
I don't know if you saw any of them.
这完全是精神折磨
This has been absolute emotional torture.
如果你准备好离婚了
If you're ready to have a divorce,
就把字签了
just sign the papers!
谢谢
Thank you.
你还签得真痛快啊
wow, that was so easy for you.
42号出口有家汽车旅馆
There's a motel at Exit 42.
而这起居室里有个混蛋
And there's an asshole in the living room.
我还以为我们至少能像正常人一样好好谈谈
I thought we could at least talk about this like humans.
那是我睡觉的地方
That's where I sleep.
这是什么情况
What's happening here?
她明明同意了结束关系
She agreed to end the relationship;
我都白纸黑字写下来了
I've got it in writing.
别动  别发出声响
Don't move. Don't make a sound.
你就装死  可能她就会放手了
Just play dead, and maybe she'll let go.
说实话  感觉还不赖
Actually, this isn't bad.
她很温暖  就像块巨大的火腿肉
She's warm, like a giant ham.
也许我终究还是能睡着的
Maybe I can sleep after all.
该死
Shit.
早啊  亲爱的
Morning, love.
几点了  闹钟...
What time is it? The alarm...
我给关了
Oh, I turned it off.
我想着咱们可以休息一下
I thought we could use the rest.
-我得走了  -什么  那我们什么时候谈
- I have to go.  - What? When are we gonna talk?
我们刚谈过了
We just did.
现在我得去工作了
Now I have to go to my job.
你什么时候在佩西恩斯找了份工作
Since when have you got a job in Patience?
镇医被人杀了
The town doctor was murdered.
现在我是镇医了  因为我是活人
Now I am the town doctor because I am alive.
你在老家不干医生了
You've abandoned your practice back home,
却跑到科罗拉多州扮演救死扶伤医生
and now you're in Colorado playing Dr. Fix-it?
他们只叫我万德斯本格医生
They just call me Dr. Vanderspeigle.
再见
Goodbye.
你回家之前  把垃圾带出去
Before you go home, take out the trash.
我很注重回收
I recycle.
我很生气
I am angry.
我应该早起  现在应该已经在山上
I was supposed to be up early and already on the mountain
寻找我的设备了
to search for my device.
那女人让我分心了
That woman is a distraction.
为什么这种生物会选择
Why do these creatures choose to spend their lives
跟别人一起生活
with someone else?
他们在各自的家庭里
It's bad enough they're already tethered
就已经很难互相容忍了
to each other through family.
我的族人对待家庭的方式就很正确
My people do family the right way.
我们不在乎彼此是死是活
We don't care if they live or die.
一粒白的一粒红的  就着鸡蛋吃
Take one white one and one red one with your eggs.
这黄黄的东西叫鸡蛋吗
Is that what they call these yellow things?
看起来就像大鸟在这盘子里爆炸了
Looks like Big Bird exploded on this plate.
要不是因为你  我们这会都在嗡嗡家
Wasn't for you, we'd be eating
吃半熏的香肠了
those half-moke sausages at Bee-bee's.
我知道这里不是华盛顿  但...
Yeah, I know, it's not exactly D. C., but...
山里的空气对你有好处
the mountain air out here is good for you.
是为了这个吗
Oh, is that what we're going with?
所以我们来了这里吗
Is that why we're here?
是啊  搬来这里都怪我
Yeah, blame moving out here on me,
反正什么事都怪我
just like you blame me for everything else.
可能山姆被杀也是我的错
Probably my fault Sam got killed, too.
那案子破了吗  麦克
You crack that one yet, Mikey?
我猜也没有
Didn't think so.
看来山姆死错了镇子
Looks like Sam chose the wrong town to die in.
你...
You just...
该死
Shit!
你到底怎么回事
What's wrong with you?
这些人居然放心让你带着枪
And these people trust you with a gun.
对不起  爸爸
I'm sorry, Dad.
求你把药吃了好吗
Can you just take your pills, please?
好好好
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
哈里
Harry!
怎么了  在里面抓浣熊吗
What's going on? Chasing a raccoon in there?
我没事
I'm fine.
没有浣熊
There is no racoon.
我只是在穿裤子
I'm just putting on my pants.
不是吧
Oh, shit.
你住在你的卡车上吗
Are you living in your truck?
没什么好羞耻的
Hey, it's nothing to be ashamed of.
我每周有三天会睡在59号  我懂的
I...I sleep at the 59, like, three nights a week, so I get it.
我没住在卡车上
I'm not living in my truck.
我...
Oh, I...
我确实睡在59号
I do sleep at the 59.
这咖啡是给我的吗
Is that coffee for me?
你是说我没递给你的这杯咖啡吗
Oh, this coffee that I have not offered to you in any way?
不是给你的
No.
总之  很高兴遇见你  因为
Anyway, glad I ran into you because, um...
我们很愉快  我们接吻过
you know, we had fun, and we kissed,
那感觉  很有趣
which was...interesting.
但我觉得是时候
But I i kind of think we shouldn't drag this whole
把话说清楚了
"Will they, won't they" thing out more than we need to.
我不想再和你约会了
I don't want to date you anymore.
我能嗦一口吗
Can I just have a sip?
-这能帮助我排便  -好吧
- It will help me move my bowels. - Okay.
我知道你此刻很受伤
No, I can see that you're hurting,
也很理解
and I get it.
我们能做朋友  只是
We can be friends, I just it's just...
你不是我的菜
You're just not my type.
就是说  这世上最聪明
So your type is not the smartest
最好的男人不是你的菜
and the best person in the world.
看吧
See, there it is.
你的这种自恋
I think it's just your ego.
就像
It's...
我甚至都不知道该怎么形容
I don't even know how to describe it.
看来你不是很聪明
So you're not very smart?
我他...你说什么
what the...?Did you just say to me?
糟了  人类男人不能对女人太刻薄
Oh, no. Human men must not say mean things to women.
如果不道歉  她会发现我是外星人
If I don't apologize, she'll know I'm an alien.
刚刚太刻薄了
That was mean.
我不该那样说的
I should not have said that.
没错
Yeah.
我是男人  一个人类男人  你很聪明
I am a man, a human man, and you are smart,
相对于
relative to...
我们种族来说
our species.
再见
Goodbye.
混蛋
Asshole!
你这个渣男竟然骗我
You lying, cheating bastard.
山姆·霍奇斯病人档案
你好  万德斯本格医生
Oh, hello, Dr. Vanderspeigle.
没想到你还在这儿
I'm surprised you're still here.
霍索恩镇长还没找到替代我的医生
Mayor Hawthorne hasn't found my replacement yet
因为他办事效率低
because he's bad at his job.
这些是山姆的私人医疗档案
Well, these are Sam's private medical files.
我想你可能会需要
I thought you might want them.
不用了
No.
不过好吧
But okay.
既然我都在这儿了
You know, since I'm here,
请问你完成山姆的尸检报告了吗
can I ask if you've finished Sam's autopsy report?
我得等到丹佛实验室那边的
I can't until I get the toxicology results
毒物检测结果才能知道
back from the lab in Denver.
听到他自杀了  我真的很伤心
So sad to find out he committed suicide.
他是被谋杀  就没什么好伤心的了
Because if he was murdered, it would not be so sad.
如果是自杀
Well, if he committed suicide,
将无法获得保险赔付
his insurance claim would be null and void.
我只能指望你了  医生  做正确的事吧
So I'm counting on you, Doctor, to do the right thing.
你需要剪剪头发了
You know, you could use a haircut.
不如到楼下的美发店坐坐
Why don't you come down to the salon?
我亲自给你造型
I'll cut it for you.
我都自己剪
I cut my own hair.
看得出来
I see that.
你俩说什么呢
What was that about?
她支持谋杀
She's pro-murder.
并且她希望你把这个盒子
And she wanted you to take this box
和其他死人的盒子放一块儿
to where the other dead people boxes go.
行吧
Okay, then.
霍奇斯太太带来的  我不知道该放哪里
Mrs. Hodges brought this. I don't know where to put it.
还有  我妈妈很感激
Also, my mom wanted to thank you
那晚你帮我的事
for helping me out the other night.
她想邀请你吃晚餐
She wants to make you dinner.
这很棒  她不用这么客气的
That's nice. She doesn't have to do that.
我们能详细聊聊
we can talk about that.
我先把这盒子放好
So I'm gonna take this box.
我有麻烦了
I have a problem.
我也是  这盒子甩不掉了
So do I. That box keeps following me.
我搞砸了
I messed up.
我就不该带杰伊来这里
I never should've brought Jay here.
她很无辜
She's just so innocent.
根本不知道实情
Walking around, not knowing the truth.
告诉她你是她亲妈
Tell her you're her mother.
是我丢弃了她
I gave her up.
我现在不能因为私心就这样要回她
I can't just drag her back now that it suits me.
她有自己的生活和家庭
She has a life and a family.
得等她自己想知道真相
You know, knowing the truth should be on her terms
等她准备好了
when she's ready.
杰伊不能再待在这儿了
Jay should not be here.
真有趣
This is interesting.
她想把杰伊送走是因为她爱她
She's willing to send Jay away because she loves her,
而不是因为讨厌她
not because she hates her.
炒了她
Fire her.
不行
No.
我不能这样做
I can't do that.
那我能吗
Can I?
不过
Although...
她快结课了
her class is almost over.
我能保证她取得个好成绩
I could make sure she gets a good grade.
哈里
Harry.
这条围巾是谁的
Whose scarf is this?
我面前这女人吗
Girl up front? This woman?
什么"这女人"
Excuse me. "This woman"?
哈里  请告诉你的女朋友
Harry, why don't you tell your girlfriend
这里是医生办公室
that this is a doctor's office
她不能就这样闯进来
and she cannot barge into an exam room?
我可不是女朋友
I'm not his girlfriend.
我是他老婆
I'm his wife.
老婆
His wife?
哈里跟我说过你早死了
Harry here told me you were dead.
我对你来说是死了是吗  哈里
Do I look dead to you, Harry?
那死人会这样吗
Would a dead person do this?
或这样
Or that?
对不住  那么
Ooh, I'm so sorry. All right, then.
那这怕不是见鬼了
Ooh, and this must be a ghost.
你也死了  我们都死了
You're dead, too. I guess we're all dead.
都死了
Dead!
抱歉  对了
Wow, sorry. Um, right.
你就是个恶魔
You're a monster.
我要回纽约
I I I'm going back to New York.
我不能
I I can't.
"恶魔"是个奶酪牌子吗
"Monster" Is a cheese, right?
来杯你们这儿最烈的酒
Can I have a glass of your driest white, please?
我们这儿从万圣节开始
Well, we've been using the same box of wine
就用的同一种酒  所以
as a stepladder since Halloween, so...
威士忌  你的最佳选择
whiskey... That's your best bet.
天
Oh, dear.
幸运的是
And you're in luck.
现在还算特价早餐时间
Still in time for the breakfast special,
如果你想  还能加个蛋进去
if you want me to crack an egg into it.
我是在离婚中
I am going through a divorce,
但我还没到需要"威士忌加生鸡蛋"的程度
but I'm not quite at "Egg in my whiskey" phase yet.
离婚  那的确不简单  我理解
Divorce. That's rough. I hear ya.
你离婚了吗
You're divorced?
不  还没有
Oh, no. Not yet, anyway.
有朝一日会的
You know, someday.
我还处于离婚前
Still kind of working on that pre-divorce part.
别费心了
Don't bother.
上帝  人们都是怎么...
Ah, God. How do people...
真是出其不意
Really sneaks up on you.
没错  就像是中风一样
Yeah. It's like a stroke.
我就是不明白一个人怎么可以有如此大的转变
I just don't understand how people can change so much.
他以前非常有活力而且善于展示自己
He used to be so alive and present,
而现在他  很迟钝
and now he's, like, blunt.
我懂迟钝的家伙
I know blunt guys.
我交往的那个人  就好像
Yeah, the guy I'm dating, it's like,
他很直率  这点很与众不同
he's so direct, you know, which is refreshing.
有点性感  但是
It's kind of hot, but...
有时就  就真的很无情
Sometimes it's... it's really brutal.
完全正确  上帝  他们都是一个样
Exactly. God, they're all the same.
-可能是同一个人呢  -或许  有两个他
- Probably dating the same guy. - Maybe there's two of them.
你可真能想象
Can you imagine?
不好意思  我以为你是我的老婆
I'm sorry. I thought you were my wife.
麦克斯有些事想跟你说
Max has something he would like to tell you.
说吧  麦克斯
Go ahead, Max.
我为了溜进你的小屋 偷了你的钥匙
I stole your keys and made a copy of them
并重新配了一副
to sneak into your cabin.
什么
What?
我对这个控告感到十分惊恐
I am horrified at this accusation!
不  他没有指控你什么
Oh, no, he didn't accuse you of anyth...
我不接受你的道歉
I don't accept your apology!
他还没有道歉
Well, he hasn't apologized yet.
我说的有点超前了
I'm getting ahead of myself.
麦克斯  继续说把
Max. Go on.
对不起
I'm sorry.
很好
Good.
现在  我  不接受你的道歉
Now I...do not accept your apology!
你  你必须得接受
Well, you... You have to accept it.
为什么
Why?
这是条例规定的
Those are the rules.
那他不是真的抱歉  所以我不接受这次道歉
Well, he's not really sorry, so I'm not accepting it.
万德斯本格医生说得没错
Dr. Vanderspeigle is right.
麦克斯
Max
真心说出你的歉意
say it like you mean it.
但是我并不是真心的
But I don't mean it!
你的行为愚弄不了我  外星人
Your act doesn't fool me, alien.
我知道你在你的地下室里发现了我们
I know you found us in your basement
然后用某种手段偷偷地把我们送回家
and somehow snuck us home.
我感觉我被攻击了  我很敏感的
I'm feeling attacked. I am snowflaking.
麦克斯  够了
Max, that's...that's enough.
你看到我们的情况了吧  万德斯本格医生
Do you see what we're dealing with, Dr. Vanderspeigle?
他就是不肯放下
He just won't let up.
我有个办法
I have an idea.
他们很显然疼爱这个孩子
They obviously love this kid.
我不确定为什么
I'm not sure why.
他是个威胁
He's a menace.
我从阿斯塔那学到爱
I learned a lesson from Asta about love.
它可以被用做武器
It can be used as a weapon.
好了  麦克斯
Okay, Max.
我将给你做一个简单的测试
I'm going to give you a simple test.
这些人中  哪一个是我
Which one of these people... is me?
你知道我没法这样辨认出你
You know I can't tell by this.
如果这里有一个恶心的外星人的照片
If there was a picture of a gross alien
或是个愚蠢的鼻涕虫  我很愿意指出来
or a dumb slug, I'd point to it.
-真伤人  -麦克斯
- Hurtful. - Max.
请别再瞎胡闹了
Please stop fooling around.
这是很严肃的
This is serious.
行吧
Fine.
-这个人  -不
- This one! - No!
别再耍把戏了  小兄弟  那个是罗素·克劳
Enough games, buddy. That's Russell Crowe.
不对  那个是山姆·尼尔
No, that's Sam Neill.
不  他是那个澳大利亚人
No, the Australian guy
演过一个关于数学天才的电影
from the genius movie with the math.
-不对  我保证  不是的  -好了
- No, I promise you, it's not... - Hey!
够了
Snap out of it!
麦克斯指错了
Max got it wrong.
甜心  他是谁
Sweetie, who is this?
-你认不出来他吗  -不
- Don't you recognize him? - No!
我这辈子从没见过这个男人
I've never seen that man before in my entire life.
我原谅你
I forgive you
闯入我的房子  麦克斯
for breaking into my house, Max.
我原谅你
I forgive you
因为你是一个生病了的小孩
because you are a sick little boy.
而且  她说对了  他是山姆·尼尔
And she's right. It's Sam Neill!
他演过侏罗纪恐龙纪录片
From the Jurassic-era dinosaur documentary!
-我  -他在说谎
- I... - He's lying!
他给我设了套  他在骗你
He's setting me up! He's tricking you!
他根本不是真的医生
He's not even a real doctor!
-麦克斯  -我玩得很开心
- Max. - Well, this has been fun.
我赶紧从窗户跳出去好了
I'm just gonna go jump out a window real quick.
麦克斯
Max.
这比我想的还要严重
It's worse than I thought.
他很显然
He obviously suffers
患有严重的"怪兽恐惧症"
from a severe case of teraphobia.
怪兽恐惧症
Teraphobia?
总是看见怪物或是其他可怕的东西
Seeing monsters and other scary things.
这是你最需要担心的
If you worry about one thing, it should be that.
另外
Also...
他可能患有脸盲症
he might suffer from face blindness
和焦虑症
and anxiety...
而且  参考你的头骨
and looking at your skull...
他有可能还会发际线后移
he's probably gonna have a receding hairline.
这太可怕了
This is horrible.
如果怪兽恐惧症没有加以治疗
If teraphobia is untreated,
麦克斯就会有很严重的问题
Max can have severe issues,
一生都没有多少头发可不是什么趣事
and going through life without hair is no fun.
但是
But...
有一所特殊学校
there is a special school
唐纳利学院
针对像麦克斯这样的小孩
for kids like Max...
在佐治亚州
in Georgia.
佐治亚州
Georgia?
唐纳利学院
我们只需要一个确凿的证据[冒烟的枪]
We just need a smoking gun.
我们没有找到烟  甚至  我们连枪都没找到
We ain't got no smoke. Hell, we ain't even got a gun.
我询问了所有可能的目击证人
I interviewed every possible witness,
我也检查了所有证物  我
and I examined all the evidence. I...
你现在在逗我玩吗
Are you shitting me right now?
你在玩悠悠球吗
Are you playing with a yoyo?
抱歉  长官  它  它能让我冷静
Sorry, sir. It, uh...it calms me.
我也需要冷静  把它给我
Well, I need to be calm. Give me this.
没有可能的嫌疑人
Got no viable suspects.
没有动机  我们什么都没有
We got no motive. We got nothing!
该死  我们甚至还不能确定
Hell, we don't even know for sure yet
他是否是被谋杀的
if he was even murdered!
真棒  你把它弄坏了
Great, you broke it.
长官  山姆不像是会自杀的人
Sir, Sam doesn't seem the suicide type.
我觉得他是被谋杀的
I think he was murdered,
我也认为那和湖里的脚有关
and I really do think it's somehow related to the foot in the lake.
别管那只脚了
You know what? Screw that foot.
据我们所知  那玩意是从北边顺流而下的
For all we know, that thing floated downriver from up north.
现在甘尼森可能有个一只脚的混蛋
There's probably some one-footed sumbitch up in Gunnison,
正单脚跳着嘲笑我们呢
hopping around, laughing at our asses right now.
我不觉得他还能笑得出来
I don't think he laughs much.
我以为有连环杀手时  太开心了
I was so happy when I thought we had a serial killer.
感觉很棒
It felt good.
看看这些街道
I mean, look at these streets!
一点也不危险  漂亮极了
They're not mean! They're beautiful!
你知道科罗拉多斯普林斯
You know how many violent crimes
去年有多少起暴力犯罪吗
Colorado Springs had last year, hmm?
超过五百起
Over 500.
五百
500!
幸运的混蛋们
Lucky bastards.
别灰心  长官  明天是宾果之夜[猜数字游戏]
Cheer up, sir. Tomorrow is bingo night.
拉贝勒太太说不定又会突然开始揍神父
Maybe Mrs. Labelle will sucker‐punch the priest again.
她比西葫芦蛋糕还疯狂
Yeah, she is crazier than zucchini cake.
是啊
Yeah.
其实她是我姨妈
Actually, s‐she is my aunt.
好吧  那也不能在蛋糕里放蔬菜
Okay. Still shouldn't put vegetables in cake.
那样不对
It's wrong.
我们是聪明有魅力的独立女性
We're smart, attractive, independent women.
不需要什么臭男人决定我们的未来
We don't need some guy to determine our future.
我们很坚强
We are strong!
我们很坚强  我们无所畏惧
We're strong. And we're fearless!
你无所畏惧
You are fearless!
说的太对了
Damn right.
除了这个家伙
Except about this guy.
我觉得你和他分手
I think you broke up with him
是因为你害怕受到伤害
because you were afraid of getting hurt.
你是这么想的吗
You think so?
我还以为是因为
'Cause I thought it was 'cause
他接吻就像马吃甜筒冰淇淋
he kissed like a horse eating an ice cream cone.
实在抱歉
I'm so sorry.
-每个真男人都会爱上你的  -是啊
- Any real man would be in love with you. - Yeah.
相信我这个艺术家
Take it from an artist.
没有风险  就没有收获
Without risk, there's nothing.
确实
Yeah.
真正的女人不会逃避
Real women don't run away.
没错
That's right.
我们不逃避
We don't run away.
因为我们很坚强  因为我们互相支持
Because we're strong because we support each other.
没错
Right.
你见到丹尼了吗
Have you seen Danny?
白天就喝得醉醺醺  修点歌机的丹尼吗
Day Drunk Danny that fixes the karaoke machine?
天啊  朱迪
Jesus, Judy.
你只是嫉妒我有个手指伸进小洞也很灵活的男友
You're just jealous I got a guy who can work in tight spaces.
说得你真有似的
Like you have any.
你不想知道吗
Oh, wouldn't you like to know?
全镇都知道  朱迪
The whole town knows, Judy!
我知道
I know.
-你好啊  -你好
- Hello. - Hello.
真漂亮
Pretty.
-伙计们  -敬互相扶持的女人
- You guys! - To women supporting women.
干杯
Yes.
杰伊
Hey, Jay.
谢谢你把文件捡起来
Thanks for picking up the files.
我知道你很喜欢这里
I know you like it here,
而且和你相处也很愉快
and it's really been great having you.
我们只是...
Um, we're just...
我们没有几个月前那么忙了
we're not as busy as we were a couple months ago.
你在听我说话吗
Are you listening to me?
这个文件上说你有个孩子
This paper says you had a baby.
而且你的孩子和我同一天生
And your baby was born on my exact birthday.
没关系  反正我知道自己是被领养的
It's fine. It's not like I didn't know I was adopted.
我...
I...
这很...
It's...
这很复杂
it's complicated.
你知道吗...
You know...
好像也不怎么复杂...
it seems simple.
你先是把我送走  然后又对我撒谎
You gave me away and then lied to me.
等等
Wait.
如果你是我的亲生母亲  那我的亲生父亲是谁
If you're "Mommy", and who's "Daddy"?
不会是那个混蛋吉米吧
It's not that dick Jimmy, is it?
我一下子就猜中了  对吧
I really won the lottery with that one, didn't I?
难怪你要把我送走
No wonder you gave me away.
-我真的很抱歉  -不必了
- I'm so sorry ‐ Don't.
我本来刚要炒她的
I was going to fire her.
佩西恩斯
科罗拉多州
你在等公交车吗
Are you waiting for a bus?
我喜欢寒冷  能帮助我思考
I like the cold. It helps me think.
佛教僧人认为持续思考使人痛苦
Buddhist monks believe that suffering comes from the thinking mind.
他们还能锻炼大脑免受痛苦
They can also train their minds not to feel pain.
其中一个人自焚了
One of them lit himself on fire.
我觉得他肯定感到痛苦了
I think that one felt pain.
你在试图宽慰我吗
Trying to make me feel better
我可是刚伤透了一个十七岁女孩的心
after tearing the heart out of a 17‐year‐old girl?
你没有伤她的心
You didn't tear her heart out.
你只是骗了她  假装是她朋友
You just lied to her and pretended to be her friend.
你想讨论骗人的事吗
You want to talk about lying?
什么样的人会谎称自己妻子死了
What kind of person lies about their wife being dead?
人类就是会说谎
Humans lie.
这是他们的天性
It's what they do.
为什么
Why?
或许他们不想让别人看清自己的真实面目
Maybe they don't want people to know who they really are.
我说了在餐馆见
I told you I'd meet you at the diner.
我也很高兴见到你
Nice to see you, too.
我是哈里·万德斯本格  我想我们见过一面
Harry Vanderspeigle. I think we met briefly.
你想找茬吗  伙计
Are you fu‐‐ with me, man?
当然不是
No, of course not.
真是个怂蛋
Chicken‐ass bitch.
好了  走吧
Okay. Let's go.
咱们走
Let's go!
别这样
Don't.
我不是为了这个联系你
That is not why I texted you.
你总是这么说
You always say that.
你得听我说
I need you to listen.
很难开口  事关那个孩子
This is hard. It's about the baby.
她发现了我们的身份
She found out who we are.
她是怎么知道你的
How did she find you?
是杰伊
It's Jay.
接电话的那个坏脾气女孩吗
The girl with the attitude that answers the phone?
对  她是我们的女儿
Yeah. She's our daughter.
没错  我雇她的时候就知道
And, yes, I knew that when I hired her.
天啊  阿斯塔
Jesus, Asta.
你是怎么搞的
That is messed up.
他在这里做什么
What the hell is he doing here?
他是你新男友还是怎样
What, is he your new boyfriend or something?
-不是  -不是
- No. - No.
我只是来这里吃蛋糕
I'm just here eating cake.
-你现在成她的保镖了吗  -哈里
- You her bodyguard now? - Harry.
-我更喜欢你叫我忍者  -哈里
- I prefer ninja. - Harry.
你没必要这么做的  无视他就好了
You don't have to do this. Just ignore him.
你不应该无视忍者
You shouldn't ignore ninjas.
你不要理睬他就好了
Just don't pay any attention to him.
他最近在读跟僧侣和忍者相关的书
He's reading books about monks and ninjas.
你知道多久了
How long have you known?
一直知道
Always.
从你劝我送走我自己的孩子开始
Since you talked me into giving up my own baby.
该死  阿斯塔
Damn it, Asta!
你当时也没准备好
You weren't ready either!
你认真的吗
Are you serious?
我告诉你  只是因为想让你先从我口中得知
I'm only telling you so that you will hear it from me first.
如果杰伊来找你
If Jay comes to find you,
我不想你冲她发火
I don't want you flipping out on her.
你是她人生中最不需要的人
You're the last person she needs in her life.
行啊
Oh, right.
你总是把我说成神经病
You always make me out to be the psycho.
知道吗
You know what?
你自己之前做的事也不正常
Doing what you did, that shit ain't normal.
你真的想要保护她的话
You really wanted to protect her,
你根本就不应该走进她的生活
you should've stayed the hell out of her life.
她知道真相的话更好
It's better that she knows.
这不是你的问题
This isn't your problem.
不应该由你来解决
You shouldn't have to deal with it.
你当时太小了  记不住
You're too young to remember...
但是那一晚
but that night,
在我意识到你妈妈不回来之后
when I realized your mother wasn't coming back,
我把你抱得更紧  并对你发誓
I tucked you in extra tight, and I made a promise to you
我永远不会让你独自一人面对自己的人生
that I'd never leave you to do this life alone.
我怎么能离开她
How could I leave her?
你当时也没有更好的主意
Well, you didn't know any better.
但是我向你保证
But I promise you,
她有一个爱她的家
she has a family that loves her
他们将她视如己出
as if she was their own.
哈里去哪了
Where did Harry go?
忍者
Ninja.
她为什么还在这里
Why is she still here?
她在我家的话
How am I supposed to get into my underwear
我该怎么只穿着内裤看杰里·奥尔巴赫
and watch Jerry Orbach with that hot ham in my house?
你说过你会永远离开的
You said you were going away forever.
恐怕我今天是有点失态
I'm afraid I didn't handle things very well today.
我真的很想能补偿你
I'd really love to make it up to you.
希望你饿了
Hope you're hungry.
你从哪里拿到的这些牛排
Where did you get these steaks?
从楼下的冷冻柜里
They were in the freezer downstairs.
这不可能  因为门是
That's impossible, because the door is...
开着的
Open!
怪胎  我不知道你为什么把一切都锁起来
You freak, I don't know why you locked everything like that.
我觉得我们在这里不用这样
I don't think we have to do that out here.
我不得不把冰柜的锁给撬开
I had to break the lock of the icebox
好拿到  牛排
just to get the...steaks.
还得去拿些冻豌豆
Got to get some frozen peas.
我去拿
I'll get them.
你真好
You're lovely.
你真安静  你在想什么
You're so quiet. What are you thinking?
想我能不能把你的尸体塞进冰柜
If I could fit your body in the freezer
和另一个家伙放在一起
next to the other guy.
想很多事情
So many things.
你完全不一样了
You're so different.
自从我来到这以后  你就很不像原来的你
You haven't been yourself since I got here.
我就是我
I am myself.
我一直都是我
I've always been myself.
一个男人
A man...
而不是别的什么
and nothing else.
看  这就是我在说的
See, that's what I'm talking about.
我知道你是怎么回事
I know what's going on with you.
你在害怕
You're afraid.
这么说没错
I'll go with that.
我也很害怕
I'm scared, too.
好多人突然来到我们的公寓
Men showed up at the apartment
说他们需要跟你谈谈
and said they needed to talk to you.
听着  我不在乎你惹了什么麻烦  真的
Look, I don't care what trouble you're in. I really don't.
不管你发生了什么事情
Whatever's going on with you,
我都会在你身边  不论什么事
I'll be there with you, no matter what.
好的  达茜
All right, D'arce.
你想要孤注一掷吗
You want to put yourself out there?
那就来吧
Let's do this.
来吧  猛男  我们来跳舞
Come on, you beast. Let's have a dance.
该死
Shit.
真是浪费我的体香剂
That was a waste of deodorant.
晚餐结束了
Well, dinner's over.
接下来做什么
What next?
我只能想到一件事
I can only think of one thing.
在你离开前把平底锅洗了
Scrub the pans before you leave.
*有一位男孩*
*There was a boy*
*一位非常奇怪*
*A very strange*
*被施了魔法的男孩*
*Enchanted boy*
*他们说他游荡了好远*
*They say he wandered very far*
*好远*
*Very far*
*经过了天涯海角*
*Over land and sea*
*然后有一天*
*And then one day*
*在神奇的一天  他来到了我面前*
*One magic day, he passed my way*
*我们谈论了许多事情*
*And while we spoke of many things*
*有弄臣和国王*
*Fools and kings*
*他还对我说*
*This he said to me*
*我们能遇到最美好的事情*
*The greatest thing you'll ever learn*
*就是爱*
*Is to love*
*和被爱*
*And be loved*
*只管去爱*
*Just to love*
*只管*
*And be*
*被爱*
*Loved*
你想要把他送到佐治亚州
You want to send him to Georgia?
我当然不想把他送走
Of course I don't want to send him away.
但是我们的孩子精神出了问题
But we have a broken child.
唯一比将他送走更可怕的事情
The only thing scarier than being away from him
就是如果我们不采取行动  他的情况会更糟糕
is him getting worse if we don't do something about it.
但是  也许他长大后就好了
But maybe he'll outgrow it on his own.
就像吐字不清和...和吮大拇指一样
You know, like the lisp or the‐‐or the thumb sucking.
不  我觉得
No. I just‐‐I think‐‐
我觉得  我们应该给他更多时间
I just think that we should give it more time.
这不一样
This is different.
那个地方是专门帮助他的  而我们做不到
This place is equipped to help him in ways that we can't.
说实话
Be honest.
你觉得麦克斯是个正常的小孩吗
Does Max seem like a normal little boy to you?
不  我想不是
No, I‐I guess not.
我是不是掉发了
Am I losing my hair?
什么  没有  怎么突然
What? No. What?
你不觉得我的发际线往后退了一点吗
Don't you feel like it's gone back a little bit?
没有
No.
《圣餐》
一个真实的故事
麦克斯呼叫萨哈尔  你听到了吗
Max for Sahar. Do you read me?
萨哈尔收到  完毕
Sahar here, over.
我知道你不相信我说的关于外星人的事
I know you don't believe me about the alien.
我父母要把我送走了
My parents are sending me away.
完毕
Over.
我只是说我不记得
All I said was that I didn't remember.
我当然还是相信你的
Of course I still believe you.
没人要把你送走
And nobody's sending you away.
我有一个主意  完毕
I have an idea. Over.
不需要害怕
There's no need to be frightened.
我会照顾好你的
I'll take care of you.
告诉巴贝特哪里疼
Tell Babette where it hurts.
我不知道巴贝特是谁...
I don't know who Babette is‐‐
感觉好棒
Ooh, that feels good.
天啊  你真帅
God, you're handsome.
你也是
So are you.
我不知道我们在干什么
I don't know what we're doing.
我们在重燃爱火
We're reconnecting.
我就知道你依然爱着我
I knew you still loved me.
你甚至不想把那个取下来
Didn't have the heart to take it down.
我们将会永远在一起的
We're gonna be together forever.
我以为你现在应该在佐治亚州被肛测了
I thought you'd be in Georgia by now getting probed.
人类才不会肛测  只有愚蠢的外星人才会这么干
Humans don't probe. Only stupid aliens do that.
我们的人不会这么干
My people don't.
灰种才喜欢屁股
It's the greys that have the ass fetish.
只有大人之间才能说这种话  我们不喜欢
That's adult language, and we don't appreciate it.
你来这里干什么
What are you doing here?
你见到我不该这么惊讶
You shouldn't be that surprised to see me.
碰到你那浮在空中的苹果也许是消除了我的记忆
Touching your floating apple may have knocked out my memory,
但没有弄死我
but it didn't kill me.
也许下次就会了
Maybe next time.
不会再有下次了
There won't be a next time.
别  麦克斯  大人说话呢
Hold on, Max. The adults are talking.
麦克斯不会去那个机构
Max isn't going to that institute.
我曾经为了逃离苏菲祈祷圈
I once held my breath for two minutes
憋气整整两分钟
just to get out of a Sufi prayer circle.
我会教他的
I'll teach him.
我敢打赌他将憋气一小时
I'll bet he'll hold his breath for an hour
成功逃出佐治亚州
to get out of Georgia.
很好  那他肯定死了
Good. Then he'll be dead.
我会找到他的坟墓并吐上口水
I'll find his tombstone and spit on it.
你没办法那么做
You won't be able to
因为他将会被火化
because he's going to be cremated
骨灰将会撒进海里
and have the ashes sprinkled into the ocean.
很好  那我也吐上口水  吐在你DNA上
Fine. Then I'll spit on it, and it'll hit your dead DNA.
不  那也不可能  因为我骗了你
No, it won't. Because I tricked you.
他的骨灰没有被撒进大海
He didn't really have his ashes put into the ocean.
我藏在了你的口袋里
I snuck them into your pocket.
所以你往大海里吐口水时
So, when you were spitting into the ocean,
他就一直在你的口袋里嘲笑你
he was in your pocket laughing at you the whole time.
你的口水永远不可能吐中他
Your spit will never get near him.
我们又赢了
We win again.
吐中了
I got you.
我觉得我刚刚做的应该
I don't think what I just did was...
不是正常的人类行为
normal human behavior.
我们把你逼疯了吗
Are we driving you crazy?
赶紧习惯吧
Get used to it.
我们俩都会憋气
We're both holding our breath
等你保证你会永远不会烦他
until you promise to leave him alone.
等我们晕过去了  他们就会觉得是你干的
When we pass out, they'll think you did it.
很好  那样安静多了
Good. It'll be quieter.
太好了  我有更多空气了
Great. More air for me.
谢谢  我要再来点
Thank you. I'll have some more.
你们看上去好蠢
You look silly.
听着  你们还要憋多久
Look, I mean, how long is this?
好吧
Okay.
好了  停下
Okay, stop!
-你们想要什么  -休战
- What do you want? - A truce.
你和我爸妈说我没有疯  让我能继续留在家里
You tell my parents I'm not crazy so I can stay home,
我就不会告诉所有人你是外星人
and I'll stop telling everyone you're an alien.
杀掉他行不行  我还能杀掉他吗
What about killing him? Can I still kill him?
不行
No!
"休战"这个词就暗示了这一点
That's pretty much implied in the word "truce."
来吧
Go ahead.
握手言和
Shake on it.
好吧
Fine.
还有什么问题吗  麦克斯
Any questions, Max?
有  我为什么能看到你
Yeah. Why can I see you?
你了解多空间时空穿梭吗
Are you familiar with multidimensional space travel?
很了解
Very.
有的人基因上就和其他空间的频率
Some humans are genetically more tuned
更加和谐
to the frequencies of other dimensions,
所以他们能看穿我们的分子构造
so they can see beyond my molecular reconstruction.
就像那件蓝黑的衣服
Like that was blue and black
但有的人觉得那是白金的
but some people saw it as white and gold?
那不是白金的吗
It wasn't white and gold?
不是
No!
我有一个问题
I have a question.
人类吃披萨的时候为什么要折起来
Why do humans fold pizza when they eat it?
基础工程学
Basic engineering.
平摊着吃太软了
It's too floppy when it's flat.
纳斯卡地画到底是什么
What are the Nazca lines?
古老的外形涂鸦
Ancient alien graffiti.
外星人会大便吗
Do aliens poop?
人人都会大便
Everybody poops.
跟书上说的一样  我就知道
Just like the book. I knew it.
我刚发现麦克斯发现了我本来的身份时
When I first discovered that Max knew who I really was,
我很恨他
I hated him for it.
也许我其实并不恨他
Maybe I did not actually hate him.
我只是恨他给我带来的感受
I just hated how he made me feel inside.
我感到暴露在众人眼中  非常脆弱
I felt exposed, vulnerable.
也可以说是我憎恨我自己
In a way, I hated myself.
但是和这些孩子聊了短短十分钟后
But after talking to those kids for just ten minutes,
我就感觉到我的恨烟消云散了
I could feel my hatred going away.
也许还有比恨更加强大的东西
Maybe there's something out there stronger than hate.
饿了吗
Hungry?
我的钱只能买得起一杯咖啡
I've only got enough for coffee.
没关系
Well, that's okay.
家人之间不用付钱
Family don't pay.
既然这样  我要两个汉堡
In that case, I'll get two burgers‐‐
一个堂吃  一个带走
one for here and one to go‐‐
还有一块派
and a slice of pie.
好的
Yeah, all right.
警长
Sheriff?
山姆的毒理报告出来了
Sam's toxicology results are in.
肉毒杆菌毒素A的含量水平超高
Botulinum toxin A levels are through the roof.
山姆是被毒死的
Sam was poisoned.
上帝老爷啊  我们这儿出了个杀人凶手
Holy shit sticks! We got ourselves a murder!
-副警长  -是  警长
- Deputy. - Yeah. Sheriff.
-好了  继续查  -好
- All right. Get on it. - Okay.
-继续  -嗯  请享受你的早餐
- Get on it. - Yeah. Enjoy your breakfast.
-好  谢谢  女士  -好
- All right, thank you, ma'am. - Okay.
我对她有很多感觉
I feel many emotions about this one.
我觉得和她很亲近
I feel close to her.
但有时候  我希望能远一点
Yet sometimes, I want to be far away.
我不恨她
I don't hate her.
我只是...需要...睡眠
I just...need...sleep.
看来能让她再多活一天
I guess she can live another day.